Taha Mousavi

Product Designer

Portfolio: tahamousavi.github.io
Email: taha.mousavi@gmail.com
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/tahamousavi

ABOUT ME

In 8 years, I've worked in the successful startups and companies in Iran like; <u>Divar, TAPSI</u>, <u>Torob</u>, and <u>Porsline</u>. After working as a multi-disciplinary designer and designing products used by millions of Iranian people, I am eager to work with international and multicultural companies. I want to learn more about other cultures and nations and design products with and for them.

EXPERIENCE

Porsline, Product Design, 2021 - Present

After a successful lunch in July 2017, I rejoined Porsline in 2021. Porsline is a SaaS company for creating online surveys, which helps companies in market research, customer experience research, and employee surveys.

- Adapting products for lunch in the Middle East countries.
- Branching design to the market research team to improve the products for more diverse users and new business demands.

Porsline Website

Torob, Product Designer, 2020 - 2021, Contracted

Torob is a shopping search engine that allows users to find the best price of products in online stores in Iran. I directly worked with the Founder, CTO, and 4 Engineers to redesign products.

- Redesigning overall interfaces of the Torob website and Android app.
- Creating two revenue streams by redesigning core experiences.
- Developing a data-driven approach in product design.
- Improving UX by several A/B tests.

Torob Website, Torob app on Google Play

Miare, Product Designer, 2018 - 2021

Miare is an on-demand delivery solution for restaurants. In the startup team, We designed the interface and experience of four products from scratch; Restaurant web app, Courier android app, and two web panels for live fleet monitoring.

From the first days, We had a problem-solving mindset, did several usability tests, and got a data-driven approach to product design.

- Designing four products from scratch on web and android platforms.
- Creating several prototypes for user research.
- Planning several usability tests for evaluating design ideas.
- Communicating with the sale and customer support teams and getting feedback.
 Miare Website

TAPSI, Product Designer, 2017 - 2018

TAPSI is a mobile transportation platform in Iran. My role at the startup team was designing MVPs and prototypes of passengers application.

- Designing UI of passenger and driver app.
- Planning and performing tests for evaluating design ideas.
 TAPSI app on Google Play

Porsline, Product Designer, 2016 - 2017

Porsline is a SaaS startup for building online forms and surveys. We designed and developed MVP by Founder, CTO, and two engineers for six months and successfully lunched the product.

- Designing prototypes for user and market research.
- Designing UI and UX of a SaaS product from scratch.
- Successful lunch of product.

Porsline Website

Divar, Product Designer, 2015 - 2016

I was responsible for enhancing the design of client-side products. I worked with PMs and engineers to improve the users' experience and create consistency on all products.

- Redesigning interface of iOS, Android, and web app.
- Evangelizing user experience design and data-driven approach to product design.
- Improving user experiences on the iOS app by gathering and analyzing data.

Divar Website, Divar app on App Store, Divar app on Google Play

Cafe Bazaar, Product Designer, 2014 - 2015

I was responsible for user interface design, visual design, and Front-End Development of the ADAD startup product. I worked directly with PM to make prototypes and do usability tests.

SKILLS

- Designing high-fidelity interfaces with **Sketch**, **Figma**, **and Axure**.
- Planning and performing Usability Tests and User Interviews.
- Working experience with different UX and research methods: A/B Test, Persona building,
 Field Study, Journey Mapping, Writing User Stories, Surveys.
- Analyzing data with Amplitude, Google Analytics, and Microsoft Excel.
- Designing Prototypes with inVision, Principle, and Framer.
- Product and task management with Jira, Trello, GitLab, and ClickUp.
- Working experience with Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, and Procreate for visual design.
- Web development with HTML and CSS.
- Familiar with declarative user interface development like React and SwiftUI.
- Familiar with Processing language and Generative Art.

EDUCATION

Sharif University of Technology,
Master of Science, Aerospace Engineering, 2009 - 2011
Civil Aviation Technology College,
Bachelor of Science, Aircraft Maintenance Engineering, 2005 - 2009

PUBLICATIONS

"The Effect of Small Scale on the Pull-in Instability of Nano-Switches Using DQM" International Journal of Solids and Structures, 2013, Citation Indexes: 61

"Nonlinear Dynamic Analysis of SWNTs Conveying Fluid Using Nonlocal Continuum Theory" Structural Engineering and Mechanics, 2018

COURSES

Human-Computer Interaction at Coursera, UC San Diego, The Design Lab **Creative Programming** at Coursera, Goldsmiths, University of London